OWOLABI ADENIRAN

LAGOS, NIGERIA

+2348097219648 • oadeniran82@gmail.com

• Github • LinkedIn •

Summary

Extremely groomed Machine learning software developer with great problem solving skills. 3yrs+ implementing a wide range of industry standard machine learning solutions over the years, including deep learning architectures and working with standard machine learning development tools such as sklearn, tensorflow. Critical thinker and problem solver who can work effectively with a team and meet targets and deadlines as at when due

Education

Obafemi Awolowo University

In View • Bsc Mechanical Engineering

Udacity

2022 • Cloud Developer with AWS

- Created a full stack web app to post images and filter the picture using AWS. GitHub
- Refactored a monolith application into micro services using Aws, docker and kubernetes. <u>GitHub</u>
- Develop and deploy a todo app sing aws lambda and the serverless framework. <u>GitHub</u>

Experience

Devops Engineer • August 2022 – Present

Hamoye • Remote

- Worked with a team of developers to implement a ML model to predict the overall score of a university based on different features.
 - Achieved an MAE of 3.6 on a scale of predictions from 0 to 100.
 - > Came 1st, above other 19 other teams who presented their final models to the organization
 - > Spearheaded a team of 6 for the deployment of the model to the web using python frameworks and heroku. Github.

Data Engineer • Jan 2022 – Apr 2022

Hamoye • Remote

- Collaborated with a team of 13 developers to implement a machine learning model to predict the additional costs after scholarship for students in universities in China. Github.
 - > Achieved an MAE of 985.46 on scale of predictions between 1000 and 30,000
- Learned and improved on the fundamentals of feature engineering and data manipulation for machine learning purposes
 - > This knowledge was used to increase the performance of a machine learning model, by reducing the MAE from 95.6 to 44.8 on the first trial.

Projects

Movie Recommendation System: A web app to recommend movie to users.

June 2022 - Aug 2022

• I implemented the recommendation system using KNN algorithm with a focus on the genre of each movie. The nature of the project was an unsupervised learning task, therefore there were no official metric to perform evaluation. Reviews from users cited optimal recommendations based on movies they had seen once. The app was deployed to the web using Heroku. Github.

Facial Recognition System: A neural network to automatically detect facial recognition

Aug 2022 – Sep 2022

- I implemented for a client, a neural network which learnt to detect and automatically classify 7 classes of facial expression using convolution neural network and experimenting with the combination of recurrent and convolution neural network layers.
- I employed a transfer learning paradigm using popular models like Vgg16, ResNet and combined the output of the models with LstM layers and dense layers to perform the classification.
- The model achieved an accuracy of 72%, which was more than the benchmark for the dataset used and also more than numerous previous approaches on the dataset used.

Skills

Languages

Python (proficient), Typescript (basic), javascript (basic), PDDL (proficient).

Tools:

AWS (proficient), Kubernetes (moderate), Docker (moderate), Linux (moderate), Anconda (proficient), Jupyter-Notebook(proficient)

Frameworks

Tensorflow (proficient), Pytorch (moderate), Sklearn (proficient), Pandas(proficient), Numpy(proficient), Open-cv(moderate), pillow(moderate), Flask(proficient), Django(moderate), seaborn(moderate), Matplotlib(proficient), Nodejs(basic).

Certifications

<u>Udacity</u> – Python Programming Foundations

Udacity - Aws Machine Learning Foundations 2022

<u>Nvidia</u> - Fundamental of DL

<u>Coursera</u> – Introduction to Deep Learning (Hse University)

<u>Freecodecamp</u> – Machine learning with python

<u>Udacity</u> – ALX-T cloud developer